Herbert Halpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Herbert Halpert's fieldwork
  - Subseries 8: Sound recordings
    - Sub-subseries 14: New York State, 1941
      - George Edwards, AFC 2004/008: SR203; IDB 44722; 9; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George Edwards, AFC 2004/008: SR204; IDB 44723; 10; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Marvin Yalley [?], AFC 2004/008: SR205; IDB 44724; 11; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Marvin Yalley [?], AFC 2004/008: SR206; IDB 44725; 12; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George Edwards, AFC 2004/008: SR207; IDB 44726; 13; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George Edwards, AFC 2004/008: SR208; IDB 44318; 14A; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
      - probably George Edwards, AFC 2004/008: SR209; IDB 44319; 14B; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
      - Walden Van Waggner; Vernon Tompkins, AFC 2004/008: SR210; IDB 44320; 15A; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
        Walden and Vernon are father and son
      - probably Walden Van Waggner and/or Vernon Tompkins, AFC 2004/008: SR211; IDB 44321; 15B; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
      - no available information, AFC 2004/008: SR212; IDB 44322; 16A; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
      - Chauncey Blackmore, AFC 2004/008: SR213; IDB 44323; 16B; 1 sound disc: aluminum; analog, 10 in.
      - Chauncey Blackmore, AFC 2004/008: SR214; IDB 44727; 17A; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Chauncey Blackmore; Art Tyler; Walter "Hasher" Howard, AFC 2004/008: SR215; IDB 44728; 18; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
    - Sub-subseries 15: Miscellaneous dubs of recordings
      - Carl Lathrop; Perry Allen, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR246; IDB 44759; 1; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Carl Lathrop; Perry Allen, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR247; IDB 44760; 2; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Perry Allen; Earl Beeb; Carl Lathrop, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR248; IDB 44761; 3; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Carl Lathrop, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR249; IDB 44762; 4; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William McBride, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR250; IDB 44763; 5; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William McBride, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR251; IDB 44764; 6; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William McBride, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR252; IDB 44765; 7; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William McBride, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR253; IDB 44766; 8; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William McBride, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR254; IDB 44767; 9; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - anonymous singer, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR255; IDB 44768; 1; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - anonymous singer, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR256; IDB 44769; 2; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Abraham Lincoln Gary, 1942, AFC 2004/008: SR257; IDB 44770; 3; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Abraham Lincoln Gary, 1942, AFC 2004/008: SR258; IDB 44771; 4; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Mrs. Buell; Miss Irene Maitlen; Mrs. Maitlen, 1942, AFC 2004/008: SR259; IDB 44772; 5; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Gloria Maitlen; Mrs. Buell, 1942, AFC 2004/008: SR260; IDB 44773; 6; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
    - Sub-subseries 16: Unidentified discs
      - Art Tyler and Walter Howard, August 18, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR216; IDB 44729; 19; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George Swartwout; Miss Sarah Winters, August 19, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR217; IDB 44730; 20; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - William Wormuth; Rick Merchant's daughter, August 20, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR218; IDB 44731; 21; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - [song titles only; no performer or date], undated, AFC 2004/008: SR219; IDB 44732; 22; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Reuben Edwards, August 21, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR220; IDB 44733; 23; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Walter Wormuth, August 22, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR221; IDB 44734; 24; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Walter Wormuth; George Swarthout, August 22, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR222; IDB 44735; 25; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Walter Wormuth, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR223; IDB 44736; 26; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Walter Wormuth; Tom Kelly, August 22-23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR224; IDB 44737; 27; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Tom Kelly, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR225; IDB 44738; 28; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Tom Kelly, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR226; IDB 44739; 29; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Tom Kelly; Chauncey Blackmore, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR227; IDB 44740; 30; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Chauncey Blackmore, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR228; IDB 44741; 31; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Chauncey Blackmore, August 23, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR229; IDB 44742; 32; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George "Dick" Edwards, August 24, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR230; IDB 44743; 33; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George "Dick" Edwards; Charles Hinckley, August 24, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR231; IDB 44744; 34; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George "Dick" Edwards; Charles Hinckley, August 24, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR232; IDB 44745; 35; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - Charles Hinckley, August 24, 1941, AFC 2004/008: SR233; IDB 44746; 36; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
      - George Gouldthorpe, circa 1906-1908, AFC 2004/008: SR310; IDB 44823; A1, A2, B1, B2; AFS 04362 A1-2, B2; AFS 04363 A2; 1 sound disc: lacquer (aluminum base); analog, 10 in.
        From the Percy Grainger cylinder duplication project (AFC 1940/014).
  - Subseries 9: Inventories and documentation for recordings
    - Sound recording disc sleeves, 211 original sleeves, most with handwritten notes. (Box 18)
    - Labels and other manuscript materials accompanying original sound recordings, 1938-1951, undated (Box-folder 17/9)
      Includes a combination of originals and photocopies.
- Series 2: Writings and conference papers
  Unless otherwise specified all writings and papers are by Herbert Halpert.
  - Singing on the Sidewalks: Folk Rhymes and Singing Games of New York City Children (1/2), 1940 (Box-folder 17/10)
    Halpert's M.A. thesis from Columbia University, submitted for publication to the University of Chicago Press and rejected. Accompanied by a copy of a letter from Violetta Halpert (dated April 2004) and a photocopy of the original folder.
  - Singing on the Sidewalks: Folk Rhymes and Singing Games of New York City Children (2/2), 1940 (Box-folder 17/11)
    See the note for Box-Folder 17/10.
  - "Folk Tales and Legends of New Jersey," 1953 (Box-folder 17/12)
    Text of a paper given by Herbert Halpert at the annual Modern Language Association meeting, on December 30, 1953. Two copies.
  - "Intensive Collecting in a Small Area: the New Jersey Pines," 1958 (Box-folder 17/13)
    Notes and documentation for a paper given by Herbert Halpert at the annual Modern Language Association meeting, on December 28, 1958.
  - "Hunting Songs and Singers in New Jersey," April 1981 (Box-folder 17/14)
    Notes on talk by Herbert Halpert
  - Published articles using material from the Indiana collection, 1949-1950, 1957 (Box-folder 17/15)
    Three published articles by Violetta Halpert.
- Series 3: Research and publicity
  Includes newspaper clippings copies of published papers, photocopies of published works requested by Herbert Halpert for his research, and accompanying correspondence and documentation.
  - Halpert collecting/collection at Murray State College (Kentucky), 1947-1956 (Box-folder 17/16)
  - Kentucky-Tennessee folklore/folkways and news (1/2), 1940-1959, undated (Box-folder 17/17)
    Most of the folder content includes newspaper clippings
  - Kentucky-Tennessee folklore/folkways and news (2/2), 1940-1959, undated (Box-folder 19/1)
    Includes programs from festivals and an exhibit.
  - Book slips and cards (Box-folder 19/2)
    From or in reference to the Allan M. Trout collections.
  - "Greetings," 1949 (Box-folder 19/3)
    From the Allan M. Trout collection. Clippings of the column "Greetings," which focused on folklore, humor, and related topics, published in the Louisville Courier-Journal
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1950 (Box-folder 19/4)
    See the note for Box-Folder 19/3.
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1951 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1952 (Box-folder 19/6)
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1953 (Box-folder 19/7)
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1954 (Box-folder 19/8)
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1955 (Box-folder 19/9)
  - "Greetings" (Allan M. Trout collection), 1956 (Box-folder 20/1)
    See the note for Box-Folder 19/3. This folder includes typed note slips, as if for a reference file.
  - Voyagers to the West, by Bernard Bailyn (excerpt), 1986 (Box-folder 20/2)
    Photocopy of the cover page, plus pages 245-259 from this book on the demand for labor in the colonial iron industry in America.
  - South Jersey Pines - description, geography, industries, 1859-1979 (Box-folder 20/3)
    Photocopies from various published sources.
  - New Jersey seashore, 1887, 1978 (Box-folder 20/4)
    Photocopied pages from Annals of Philadelphia and Pennsylvania, in the olden time, by John F. Watson; 1857; reprinted 1887.
  - Bears in New Jersey, 1907, 1982 (Box-folder 20/5)
    Photocopies of published articles.
  - New Jersey Pines, 1894-1994 (Box-folder 20/6)
    Photocopies of published articles from various sources.
  - New Jersey Pines - articles and excerpts, 1918-1987 (Box-folder 20/7)
    Includes photocopies of published materials and original programs from events.
    - Industries in South Jersey, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 20/8)
      Typescripts of research for introductory chapter on the Pines.
  - Halpert collecting in the New Jersey Pines, circa 1937-1940 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - New Jersey - newspaper clippings, 1937-1978, undated (Box-folder 20/10)
  - New Jersey Pine Barrens: articles and pamphlets, 1942-1983, undated (Box-folder 20/11)
  - "The Eternal Melody of Piney Music," by Peggy Morgan, 1984 (Box-folder 20/12)
    Photocopy of an article published in The Inquirer, the Sunday supplement to The Philadelphia Inquirer.
  - Pinelands commission - correspondence and published articles, circa 1987 (Box-folder 20/13)
    An inquiry letter from Halpert to the Pinelands Commission, and published literature and photocopies, which seem to have been sent to him as part of a response.
  - New Jersey - background, 1900 (Box-folder 20/14)
    Typed excerpts from The Daily Union History of Atlantic City and County, by John F. Hall (1900)
  - Articles on the subject of iron in the Pine Barrens, 1964, 1990, 1997 (Box-folder 20/15)
  - New Jersey iron smelting, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Pine Barrens: ecosystem and landscape, edited by Richard T.T. Forman, 1979 (Box-folder 21/2)
    Handwritten notes on a separate sheet, plus the photocopied title page and table of contents. Most of the book was photocopied; this photocopy was deaccessioned (it had no notes from Halpert)
    - Ramapo, New York, 1938 (Box-folder 21/3)
      Clipping from the New York Times about Halpert's collectiving activities.
  - "The Old Folks Say," Dr. Ruth Ann Musick, circa 1948-1949 (Box-folder 21/4)
    Newspaper clippings on West Virginia folklore
- Series 4: Student research - Indiana, 1940-1941
  - Subseries 1: Student fieldwork
    These are not formally-written papers. They are handwritten submissions from the students as the folklore collectors and/or informants. This subseries was received with papers organized alphabetically by student surname.
    - File folder and cover sheet (Box-folder 21/5)
      Photocopies
    - Adamson - Bartz (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Baxter - Bennett (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Bertza - Butler (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Conjalka - Cropp (Box-folder 21/9)
    - Davis - Dix (Box-folder 21/10)
    - Dobkins - Edwards (Box-folder 21/11)
    - Endress - Gamhill (Box-folder 21/12)
    - Geyer - Gray (Box-folder 21/13)
    - Hamilton - Higgins (Box-folder 21/14)
    - Hirsch - Irwin (Box-folder 21/15)
    - Jackson - Kerr (Box-folder 22/1)
    - Klaus - Long (Box-folder 22/2)
    - Lopp - Misch (Box-folder 22/3)
    - Moody - Myers (Box-folder 22/4)
    - McBride - Parks (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Payne - Rappaport (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Reeves - Rosenbush (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Roy - Sclipcea (Box-folder 22/8)
    - Shaikun - Specht (Box-folder 22/9)
    - Squire - Walsh (Box-folder 22/10)
    - Wampler - Zimmy (Box-folder 22/11)
    - Notes and drafts (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Subseries 2: Classified belief slips
    The order of groupings has been maintained from the order in which the materials were received.
    - Informants (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Childlore (Box-folder 23/2)
    - Dreams (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Good luck charms (Box-folder 23/4)
      From the documentation: Signs and charms involving objects (talismans)
    - Household (good and bad luck) (Box-folder 23/5)
      From the documentation: Practically all taboos
    - Household (cooking, cleaning) (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Animals, etc. (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Fish and reptiles (snakes, frogs, toads, turtles) (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Days and holidays (lucky and unlucky) (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Superstition - good luck - dreams (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Sailoring (Box-folder 23/11)
    - Sports (Box-folder 23/12)
    - Witchcraft (Box-folder 23/13)
    - Supernatural (Box-folder 23/14)
    - Funeral, death (Box-folder 24/1)
    - Legends about people (Box-folder 24/2)
    - Place names and naming stories (Box-folder 24/3)
    - Omens and premonitions (Box-folder 24/4)
    - Friendship (Box-folder 24/5)
    - Weather, courtship, marriage, planting, wishing (Box-folder 24/6)
    - Belief, cure (Box-folder 24/7)
    - Personal posessions (good and bad luck) (Box-folder 24/8)
    - Body - luck, other beliefs (Box-folder 24/9)
    - Miscellaneous (good and bad luck) (Box-folder 24/10)
    - Numbers (lucky and unlucky) (Box-folder 24/11)
    - Predicting company (Box-folder 24/12)
    - Death signs (1/2) (Box-folder 24/13)
      This section was published in "Death Beliefs from Indiana," by Violetta Maloney Halpert Midwest Folklore, Vol. 2, No. 4 (Winter, 1952), pp. 205-219.
    - Death signs (2/2) (Box-folder 24/14)
      See the note for Box-Folder 24/13.
    - Folk cures (Box-folder 25/1)
      This section was published in "Folk Cures from Indiana," by Violetta Halpert ( Hoosier Folklore Vol. 9, No. 1 (Jan.-Mar. 1950).
    - Courtship (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Wedding (Box-folder 25/3)
    - Indiana (1/4) (Box-folder 25/4)
      Part of Indiana collection A40-A41; items from other states and countries.
    - Indiana (2/4) (Box-folder 25/5)
    - Indiana (3/4) (Box-folder 25/6)
    - Indiana (4/4) (Box-folder 25/7)
- Series 5: Student research - Kentucky
  Some of the student papers are from classes taught by Violetta Halpert.
  - Subseries 1: Administrative documentation and publications
    - Murray State College - older collection documents, undated (Box-folder 26/1)
      Includes Halpert's guide to the collections from Murray State College (1948-1956), his description of the collections, and his inventory of the classified tales as he arranged them.
    - Published materials (offprints) using material from the Murray State College collection, 1949-1961 (Box-folder 26/2)
    - Murray State College - course lists of students, 1948-1956, 1991 (Box-folder 26/3)
    - First report from the Folklore Archive, 1951 (Box-folder 26/4)
    - Books abroad - received, Blackwell's, Oxford (1/3), 1948-1954 (Box-folder 26/5)
    - Books abroad - received, Blackwell's, Oxford (2/3), 1949-1955 (Box-folder 26/6)
    - Books abroad - received, Blackwell's, Oxford (3/3), 1952-1957 (Box-folder 26/7)
    - Grant books abroad - Edinburgh - received, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 26/8)
    - Note from Violetta Halpert regarding the Murray State College materials (2004 accrual), April 2004 (Box-folder 26/9)
      This noted accompanied the 2004 accrual to the collection.
  - Subseries 2: American Folklore
    - Sub-subseries 1, Winter quarter 1948
      - Adams, Virgil (Box-folder 27/1)
      - Asher, Dorothy (Box-folder 27/2)
      - Barton, Lon Carter (Box-folder 27/3)
      - Derrington, Horace (1/2) (Box-folder 27/4)
      - Derrington, Horace (2/2) (Box-folder 27/5)
      - Hughes, Martha E. (Box-folder 27/6)
      - Hurdle, Virginia Jo (1/2) (Box-folder 27/7)
      - Hurdle, Virginia Jo (2/2) (Box-folder 27/8)
      - Jones, Juanita (1/2) (Box-folder 27/9)
      - Jones, Juanita (2/2) (Box-folder 27/10)
      - Clarence Kennedy (Box-folder 28/1)
      - Edith Knepper (Box-folder 28/2)
      - Mary Clayton Long (Box-folder 28/3)
      - Jack R. Longgrear (Box-folder 28/4)
      - Lillian Lowry (1/2) (Box-folder 28/5)
      - Lillian Lowry (2/2) (Box-folder 28/6)
      - Julia Frances May (Box-folder 28/7)
      - Dove Anna McNabb (1/2) (Box-folder 29/1)
      - Dove Anna McNabb (2/2) (Box-folder 29/2)
      - Frank L. Nance (Box-folder 29/3)
      - Donald M. Prince (Box-folder 29/4)
      - Marie Rowlette (Box-folder 29/5)
      - Robert Shanklin (1/2) (Box-folder 29/6)
      - Robert Shanklin (2/2) (Box-folder 29/7)
      - Martha B. Strayhorn (Box-folder 29/8)
      - Nancy L. Taylor (1/2) (Box-folder 30/1)
      - Nancy L. Taylor (2/2) (Box-folder 30/2)
      - Clarence D. Walker (Box-folder 30/3)
    - Sub-subseries 2, Summer 1948
      - Juanita Canter (Box-folder 30/4)
      - Mrs. Agnes S. Conner (Box-folder 30/5)
      - Edna Copeland (1/2) (Box-folder 30/6)
      - Edna Copeland (2/2) (Box-folder 30/7)
      - Nora E. Crosby (Box-folder 31/1)
      - Aline Elliot (Box-folder 31/2)
      - Ione D. Haw (1/2) (Box-folder 31/3)
      - Ione D. Haw (2/2) (Box-folder 31/4)
        bills of sale at the back of the folder
      - Addie Beth Holland (Box-folder 31/5)
      - Sara B. Leonard (Box-folder 31/6)
      - Alma Lee Pentecost (Box-folder 31/7)
      - Mary Eliza Roberts (Box-folder 31/8)
      - Lucie Swift (Box-folder 32/1)
      - Miss Gene Warren (Box-folder 32/2)
      - Marian Williamson (Box-folder 32/3)
    - Sub-subseries 3, Fall 1948-1949
      - Jean Davis (1/3) (Box-folder 32/4)
      - Jean Davis (2/3) (Box-folder 32/5)
      - Jean Davis (3/3) (Box-folder 32/6)
      - Jean Erwin (Box-folder 33/1)
      - Ewing Jackson (1/4) (Box-folder 33/2)
      - Ewing Jackson (2/4) (Box-folder 33/3)
      - Ewing Jackson (3/4) (Box-folder 33/4)
      - Ewing Jackson (4/4) (Box-folder 33/5)
      - Thomas Barkely Jones (Box-folder 33/6)
      - Herman R. McLean (Box-folder 33/7)
      - Mary Louise Simons (1/2) (Box-folder 34/1)
      - Mary Louise Simons (2/2) (Box-folder 34/2)
      - Charles S. Speed (Box-folder 34/3)
    - Sub-subseries 4, Spring 1950
      - Gene Allen (Box-folder 34/4)
      - Miss Jerry Beauchamp (Box-folder 34/5)
      - Jane Dugger (Box-folder 34/6)
      - Morris E. Futrell (Box-folder 35/1)
      - Wayne Geurin (1/2) (Box-folder 35/2)
      - Wayne Geurin (2/2) (Box-folder 35/3)
      - Roy Hines (Box-folder 35/4)
      - Jane Earl Johnson (1/2) (Box-folder 35/5)
      - Jane Earl Johnson (2/2) (Box-folder 35/6)
      - Thelma Lynn Lamkin (1/2) (Box-folder 35/7)
      - Thelma Lynn Lamkin (2/2) (Box-folder 35/8)
      - Reva Lawson (1/2) (Box-folder 35/9)
      - Reva Lawson (2/2) (Box-folder 35/10)
      - Mary Julia Moore (1/2) (Box-folder 36/1)
      - Mary Julia Moore (2/2) (Box-folder 36/2)
      - Ronald P. Nielsen (1/2) (Box-folder 36/3)
      - Ronald P. Nielsen (2/2) (Box-folder 36/4)
      - Mildred Parsons (1/2) (Box-folder 36/5)
      - Mildred Parsons (2/2) (Box-folder 36/6)
      - Martha Billie Starks (Box-folder 36/7)
      - Mary Stites (1/2) (Box-folder 36/8)
      - Mary Stites (2/2) (Box-folder 36/9)
    - Sub-subseries 5, Fall 1951
      - Doris W. Castellaw (1/2) (Box-folder 36/10)
      - Doris W. Castellaw (2/2) (Box-folder 36/11)
      - Edna Earl Hobbs (1/2) (Box-folder 36/12)
      - Edna Earl Hobbs (2/2) (Box-folder 36/13)
      - Earl A. Johnston (1/2) (Box-folder 37/1)
      - Earl A. Johnston (2/2) (Box-folder 37/2)
      - William N. McElrath (1/3) (Box-folder 37/3)
      - William N. McElrath (2/3) (Box-folder 37/4)
        Includes lyrics and transcribed music, collected from the student's informant.
      - William N. McElrath (3/3) (Box-folder 37/5)
      - William L. Manning (1/2) (Box-folder 37/6)
      - William L. Manning (2/2) (Box-folder 37/7)
      - Joseph C. Miller (Box-folder 37/8)
      - Lucille S. Mitchell (Box-folder 37/9)
      - Hannah Prydatkevytch (1/2) (Box-folder 37/10)
      - Hannah Prydatkevytch (2/2) (Box-folder 37/11)
      - Wendell Rorie (Box-folder 37/12)
      - James G. Shelton (Box-folder 37/13)
      - John Stanley Shelton (Box-folder 38/1)
        Includes transcribed lyrics and music.
      - Nancy Jane Terry (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Sub-subseries 6, Fall 1952
      - Frances W. Boshears (Box-folder 38/3)
      - Jennye L. Hollowell (Box-folder 38/4)
      - Anne Penick (Box-folder 38/5)
    - Sub-subseries 7, Summer 1953
      - Joan Archer (1/2) (Box-folder 38/6)
      - Joan Archer (2/2) (Box-folder 38/7)
      - Hal F. Branson (1/2) (Box-folder 38/8)
      - Hal F. Branson (2/2) (Box-folder 38/9)
      - Elizabeth Ann Carr (1/2) (Box-folder 39/1)
      - Elizabeth Ann Carr (2/2) (Box-folder 39/2)
      - Adelaide L. Cartier (1/2) (Box-folder 39/3)
      - Adelaide L. Cartier (2/2) (Box-folder 39/4)
      - Cloar, Mrs. Doris McCombs (1/2) (Box-folder 39/5)
      - Cloar, Mrs. Doris McCombs (2/2) (Box-folder 39/6)
      - Divina Doris Key (1/2) (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Divina Doris Key (2/2) (Box-folder 39/8)
      - Joseph C. Miller (1/2) (Box-folder 39/9)
      - Joseph C. Miller (2/2) (Box-folder 39/10)
      - Mrs. Mary Ann Russell (1/2) (Box-folder 39/11)
      - Mrs. Mary Ann Russell (2/2) (Box-folder 40/1)
      - Harold F. Skaggs (1/2) (Box-folder 40/2)
      - Harold F. Skaggs (2/2) (Box-folder 40/3)
      - Mrs. Dorothy Clark Spence (1/2) (Box-folder 40/4)
      - Mrs. Dorothy Clark Spence (2/2) (Box-folder 40/5)
      - Gwendolyn C. Spiceland (1/2) (Box-folder 40/6)
      - Gwendolyn C. Spiceland (2/2) (Box-folder 40/7)
      - Originals, to be returned to Kentucky collection file (Box-folder 40/8)
        These original, handwritten papers seem to have been removed from student papers, and were meant to be interfiled on their return.
  - Subseries 3: Mythology
    - Sub-subseries 1, Spring 1952
      Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday
      - Alice Archer (Box-folder 40/9)
      - Betty Bowden (Box-folder 40/10)
      - Peggy Jean Brame (Box-folder 40/11)
      - Lois Darnell (Box-folder 40/12)
      - Richard Dewhirst (Box-folder 40/13)
      - Mary Martha Ellis (Box-folder 40/14)
      - Robert S. Griffin (Box-folder 40/15)
      - Sara Lester (Box-folder 40/16)